Saket Malpure

Software Engineer - Java | Cloud



PROFILE

Enthusiastic Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience participating in the complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications and having expertise in application development using Java, J2EE, Spring Boot, Javascript (ReactJs), AWS and related technology stack.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mastercard

Senior Software Engineer



- · Working as a Backend Developer to develop API middleware to connect Mastercard products with one of the leading foreign exchange platform.
- Engaged with design and development of REST web services using Java 11 and Spring Boot.
- Tech Java 11, Spring Boot, REST API, FIX Protocol, PostgreSQL, Spring Data, Multithreading.

Clairvoyant

Software Engineer II



Pune



May 2017 - Oct 2020

Oct 2020 - Present

- · Worked as a Full Stack Developer to develop plagiarism and grammar checking software which is based on microservices architecture.
- Responsible for designing and development of scalable, distributed microservices and web services includes business features implementation, setup and configuration of AWS infrastructure for application deployment.
- Continuous collaboration with project stakeholders for feature design and development.
- Responsible for implementation of CI/CD pipelines with AWS infrastructure.
- Tech Java 8, Spring Boot, REST, Graphql, ReactJS, MySQL, JPA, AWS (EC2, Beanstalk, Lambda, ECS, RDS, VPC, S3, SQS, SNS), Docker, Microservices, Agile Methodology (Scrum).

Accenture

Mumbai

Oct 2015 - May 2017

- Worked as a Backend Developer with an internal development team to analyze and implement the business requirements for regulatory compliance application, which is required to monitor trades which are not compliant to the rules specified by SEC (Security Exchange Commission) and may lead to fraud.
- Design and development of REST APIs and business features using Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Oracle DB.

EDUCATION

University of Pune

Associate Software Engineer

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate Level
- Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE7 Programmer
- MongoDB for Java Developers MongoDB University

SOCIAL



/saketmalpure



in /in/saketmalpure

KEY SKILLS

- Data Structures, Problem Solving
- Java 8+, J2EE, Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Web Services REST, GraphQL
- JavaScript, ReactJS
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Multithreading, Design Patterns
- AWS, Terraform
- Containers (Docker)
- Microservices
- Agile Processes, Status tracking tools (JIRA, Rally)
- CI/CD tools Jenkins, Azure Devops